connexions-direct.com 2010-11-04

# Privacy Policy - Homepage - Connexions Direct

The Connexions Direct website is provided by the Department for Education and therefore the Department's Privacy Statement applies.

The rest of this privacy statement only covers the Connexions Direct website at www.connexions-direct.com and subsequent sub-sites of that domain, www.connexions-direct.com/jobs4u/; www.connexions-direct.com/cxd-i/; www.connexions-direct.com/whichwaynow/; www.connexions-direct.com/itsyourchoice/; www.connexions-direct.com/parentcarer/. Other websites linked to or from Connexions Direct are not covered by this privacy statement. 

With the exception of the Communication channels \- service feedback form, callback request form, webchat, and email - the website does not store or capture personal information, except the logging of a user's IP addresses (Internet Protocol: standard allowing data to be transmitted between two devices) which is automatically recognised by the web server. 

## Data Protection

Under the Data Protection Act 1998, we have legal obligations towards you in the way that we deal with any data collected from you. The website uses leading technologies and, when appropriate, encryption software to safeguard your data and keep strict security standards to prevent any unauthorised access to it. 

We do not pass on your details to any third party or government department unless you give us permission to do so, or we are obliged or permitted by law to disclose it. 

## Cookies 

A cookie is a small, numeric text file that is stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive.

Connexions Direct uses cookies to help us understand how people access and navigate around the website. 

We use tracking technology which monitors user sessions via a Java applet which in turn activates a session cookie. Sessions cookies are created when you first visit the website and are deleted when you leave it. 

At certain times we use other cookies that are stored on your machine after you have left the Connexions Direct website.

Both these types of cookies do not collect any information about you except that required for system administration of the website. No information is stored on your computer and no personal data is obtained from this software.

## Cookies used for advertising and research

Connexions Direct uses pixels, or transparent GIF files, to help manage online advertising and research. These GIF files are provided by our advertising management partner DoubleClick. 

These files help DoubleClick to recognize a unique cookie on your web browser, which in turn enables us to understand how each online advertising campaign performed.

Again, the information we collect and use is anonymous and not personally identifiable. 

For more information about DoubleClick, including information about how to opt out of these technologies, go to [www.doubleclick.com/privacy](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy).

Occasionally, additional research is carried out after you have used the webchat communication channel. 

A pop-up window will appear offering you the chance to take part in an online survey. If you complete the survey or choose to opt out and close the pop-up window the survey will not appear again. If you do want the survey to appear again you will need to clear the cache of cookies on your machine.

## Want to know more about cookies?

If you would like to know more about cookies, or would like to disable cookies in your browser settings (i.e. refuse cookies) please visit www.allaboutcookies.org.
